All of a sudden, so much is happening.
突然间发生了好多事
I know. Ross is getting married.
就是啊，罗斯要结婚
Phoebe's making people.
菲比在…做人
-Everybody's doing stuff. -We just sit here.
大家都在忙 只有我们坐在这里
If I died, people would know I was here...
要是我死了 大家只会...
...only by the ass print on this chair!
从这张椅子的屁股印 知道我存在过
-What are we doing? -Wasting our lives.
我们要干嘛？ 浪费生命
I meant for lunch.
我是说午餐吃什么
We have to do something. Something huge!
我们得做一件大事
We could climb Mt. Everest.
我们可以去爬珠峰
Not something stupid. Something huge!
不是蠢事，是大事
I saw an ad for this video.
不，我在录影带上看到广告
People climb that thing every day. We could totally do that!
每天都有人在爬 我们也可以爬
Why not? I mean,it's just climbing.
谁说不行？只不过是爬山
-It's just steep! -Yeah.
只不过很陡
We're going! It'd be nice to leave an ass print on Everest.
我们去攻顶 在山顶留屁股印一定很爽
What's up?
在干什么？
-We're gonna climb Mt. Everest. -Yeah,baby!
我们要去爬珠峰 没错
I looked into that.
真的？我也去问过
Yeah,but it costs like $60,000, and,you know,you could die.
但是要花6万，而且可能会死
And you would die.
你们一定会死
We could get that Everest video.
我们可以去借珠峰的录影带
We could do that without risking our lives at all.
对，那样就不必冒生命危险
While we're at the video store, we could rent Die Hard!
到了录影带店 我们还可以借“终极警探”
I just remembered.
我刚想到
That Everest thing is only available through mail order.
那个录影带只能邮购
So you'll stay here and hang out with me?
所以你们要留下来陪我罗？ 对
But one of these days...
不过总有一天
...we'll get off our butts and rent Die Hard again!
我们会站起来 再去借一次“终极警探”
The One with the lnvitation
本集播出：“罗斯与瑞秋”
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
That was fast. It usually takes me hours to get Ben to go down for his nap.
真快，我通常要花2小时 才能让班乖乖睡觉
He's such a sweetheart. Do you know what he said?
他好可爱 你知道他刚才说什么？
-Good night,mommy. -That's because he has lots of mommies.
什么？ 妈咪，晚安 因为他有很多妈咪
Yeah,in fact,it's kind of become his word for "woman".
那算是他对女人的通称
So does your uncle Nathan get an invite or not?
怎样，请不请你的纳森叔叔？
Oh,God! Nobody likes him.
没有人喜欢他
He's so cheap. He'd never fly to London in a million years.
而且他好小器 他绝不会飞去伦敦的
Invite him!
好，请吧
Did I do these neat enough?
我写得还可以吗？
Yeah,they're fine.
可以 是吗？
We'll say that Ben addressed them.
别人问就说是班写的
You invited Rachel then?
你也请了瑞秋？
Sure,why not?
对啊，干嘛不请？
Really?
真的？
I wouldn't be comfortable having any of my old lovers there.
我找旧情人去一定会觉得蹩扭
Do you think we shouldn't invite her?
你觉得我们不该请她吗？
You know I absolutely adore Rachel.
不，我很喜欢瑞秋
It's just that I thought it might be awkward for you.
我只是怕你会尴尬
But it's absolutely your decision.
不过你决定就好
-More tea? -Sure.
还要茶吗？ 好
Earl Grey?
伯爵（茶）？
Fine,invite whoever you want.
好，你想请谁就请谁
I don't want to be single,okay? I just want to be married again.
我不想单身，好吗？我想再婚
And I just want a million dollars!
我想要1百万
Oh God,Monica. Thank God!
瑞秋？ 天哪，摩妮卡，谢天谢地
This is Rachel. Another Lincoln High survivor.
各位，这是瑞秋 她也念林肯高中
This is Chandler.
这是钱德
Phoebe.
菲比
Joey.
乔伊
-Do you remember Ross? -Sure.
你记得我哥罗斯吗？ 当然记得
Back in high school...
你或许不知道，念高中时…
...I had a major crush on you.
我非常喜欢你
I knew.
我知道
You did?
真的？
I figured you thought I was Monica's geeky brother.
我以为你只当我是 摩妮卡的怪胎哥哥
I did.
没错
Listen,do you think
你觉得…
Try not to let my intense vulnerability become a factor.
请别被我容易紧张的缺点影响
Would it be okay if I asked you out sometime?
我改天可以约你出去吗？
Maybe.
好啊…或许可以
Okay,maybe I will.
好，或许我会约
See,I see...
我看到...
...big passion in your future.
你会有一段火热恋情
-Really? -I do.
真的？ 对
Ross,you're so great.
罗斯，你真好
It's never gonna happen.
别做梦了
I have a question.
我想问个问题
Actually,it's not so much a question.
其实不算是问题
It's more of a general wondering...
比较算是一个疑惑...
...ment.
...虑
Well,for a while now, I've been wanting to....
其实我一直想要…
Yes,yes.
对
That's right.
没错
Look!
你看
What?
什么？
Top of the world looking
…世界的顶端
Down on creation
俯瞰万物
And the only explanation I can find
我唯一能找到的解释
Listen,missy! If you want this cart, you'll have to take me with it!
你给我听着 车在人在，车亡人亡
-Did you see that? -You were incredible!
你看到了吗？ 你太猛了
A brand-new woman, ladies and gentlemen.
你看到了吗？ 全新的瑞秋诞生了
I could not have done this without you.
没有你我绝对办不到
More clothes in the dryer?
好…还要烘衣服吗？
I'm fine.
我没事
You had no right to tell me you had feelings for me.
你没资格说你对我有感觉
I was doing great with Julie before I found out.
什么？ 我和茱莉原本过得很好
I was doing great too. It's not easy for me to see you with Julie.
我原本过得也很好 你以为看你们在一起很好受吗
I don't need this right now.
重点是我不想要这样 好吗？
It's too late.
来不及了
I'm with somebody else. This ship has sailed!
我有别人了，我很快乐 这艘船已经开了
All right,fine! Go ahead and do that.
好，你走啊
I don't need your stupid ship!
我不需要你这艘笨船
好 很好
This is the first time I'm doing something I care about.
我这辈子第一次做我爱做的事
I'm doing something that I'm actually good at.
做我真正在行的事
If you don't get that
要是你不懂…
I get that,but I'm tired of your answering machine.
我懂，我很懂，我为你高兴 但我不想再跟答录机交往了
I don't know what to do.
我已经没辄了
Neither do l!
我也是
Is this about Mark?
跟马克有关吗？
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
Okay,it's not.
好，不是
I can't keep having this same fight over and over again.
我的天哪 我不能为了同样的事一吵再吵
You're making this too hard!
你快把我逼疯了 好，我快把你逼疯了
I am? What do you want me to do?
你要我怎么做？
I don't know. Look,maybe we should just take a break.
我不知道… 也许我们应该分开
You're right. Let's cool off.
你说得对，我们先冷静一下
Let's get some frozen yogurt or something.
去吃点冷冻优格什么的
A break from us.
不，我是说分手
-Why are we rushing? -The girlfriend I told you about.
我们在赶什么？ 我昨晚提到的那个女朋友
She wants to get back together with me.
她想跟我复合…
I found it!
找到了
That's so great for you guys!
真是太好了
-Good luck with your girlfriend. -Thank you.
祝你复合成功 谢谢
瑞秋！
-You got my message? -You are right on time.
你听到留言了吗？ 你来得正好
Can I be your girlfriend again?
我可以再当你的女朋友吗？
You can very much.
可以得不得了
I want you to leave. Get out!
你给我走，滚
I want to talk about this.
不，我想留下来谈一谈
All right,how was she?
好，她怎么样？
-What? -Was she good?
什么？ 她厉害吗？
Don't answer!
不要回答
You wanted to talk about it. How was she?
你说你想谈，那就谈啊 她怎么样？
She was....
她…
-She was not good,not good. -Nothing compared to you.
很逊，什么也比不上你 不好
She was different.
她不一样
Good different?
好的不一样？
Nobody likes change.
没有人喜欢改变
Just stop!
别再说了
The way you owned up to everything.
你这么坦然认错
It's just showed me how much you've grown,you know?
证明你真的成长不少
I mean,my mom never thought this would work out.
我妈一直觉得我们无法复合
She was all, "Once a cheater,always a cheater."
她说：出轨一次就是一辈子
I just wish we hadn't lost those four months.
真希望没有这4个月的空白
But if time was what you needed just to gain a little perspective.
但要是时间能让你看清楚一点
We were on a break!
我们当时分手了！
（瑞秋葛林小姐收）
You seem to really like her.
你似乎真的很喜欢她
What do I do? We agreed it'd be a two-week thing.
我能怎么办？ 我们说好只在一起2星期
No commitment.
不要有承诺
That girl just spent the entire evening talking to your friends...
那个女孩整晚都跟你的朋友
...asking to hear stories about you...
嚷着要听你的事
...Iooking through Monica's photo albums.
还有看摩妮卡的相簿
You don't do that if you're just in it for two weeks.
只想在一起2周才不会这么做
You think?
是吗？
You've got 14 hours until she has to be at the airport.
她还有14个小时才要去机场
And you're sitting here in a hallway...
你却坐在走廊上
...with a 28-year-old cheerleader with a fat lip.
陪一个嘴肿起来的老啦啦队长
-You're right. -Yeah.
你说得对
This is so amazing!
真好
My brother's getting married and in London!
我哥哥居然要去伦敦结婚
It's so romantic.
好浪漫喔
Hey,pretty smart!
真聪明
Tissue paper.
附面纸
You're at the wedding. You have to cry.
参加婚礼当然会哭
Handkerchief? No,I got my invitation.
需要手帕吗？不了，我有喜帖
Isn't this adorable?
真可爱
Ross let Ben address mine.
罗斯让班写我的信封
Did you get your invitation to Ross' wedding?
你收到罗斯的喜帖了吗？
No.
没有
Don't worry,I get to bring a guest. We'll show him.
放心，我可以带一位亲友 看他怎么说
I'm so jealous you're all going.
好嫉妒你们都要去
I never knew you can't fly in your third trimester.
怀孕9个月居然不能坐飞机
I didn't,either.
我也不知道
I knew that.
我知道
So I didn't know that. But you should see your faces.
我不知道，但你们的表情好妙
What's up?
你们在干嘛？
Just hanging out.
也没干嘛
What's this? Ross' wedding invitation?
这是什么？罗斯的喜帖？
Maybe that's the one we should have hidden.
也许该藏的是那一张
No,you guys,come on. You don't have to do that.
不，不必那样
I'm happy for him.
我很替他高兴
I am. I really
真的，我很…
I'll work on it.
我会调适的
I'm sorry.
对不起
You're going to come,though, aren't you?
不过你会去吧？
I don't know.
我不知道
This isn't one of those "lf she doesn't come,we don't come"?
该不会她不去我们就不去吧？
-I bought my ticket. -You're not even invited.
我已经买票了 他根本没请你
You know what would be real weird? If you weren't there.
你不去会很奇怪
-Just say you'll think about it. -I'll think about it.
你就考虑一下吧 我会的
-Who's this from? -That's Ross'.
这是谁送的？ 罗斯送的
Oh,my God!
天哪
He remembered.
他记得
Remembered what?
记得什么？
It was months ago. We were walking by this antique store.
好几个月前 我们经过一家古董店
I saw this and told him it was like one my grandmother had...
我看到这个别针对他说
...when I was a little girl.
小时我奶奶有一个一模一样的
I can't believe he remembered!
他居然记得
This must've cost a fortune.
他一定花了很多钱
I can't believe he did this.
他居然这么大方
Remember when he fell in love with Carol...
罗斯耶，他大学爱上卡萝时
...and got her that expensive crystal duck?
就送了她一只超贵的水晶鸭
What did you just say?
你刚才说什么？
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
Flight number 457 from Beijing now arriving.
来自北京的457号班机 刚刚抵达
Oh,my God!
天哪
-We were in school together. -We haven't seen each other since.
我们是老同学 毕业后就没见过
I land in China. Guess who's in charge of the dig?
到了中国 你们猜是谁主持挖掘工作？
Julie!
茱莉
Isn't that great?
很棒吧？
Isn't that just kick-you-in-the-crotch, spit-on-your-neck fantastic?
真是老二被踹到腰去闪到的爽
That is so sweet!
你真好
No,you hang up.
不…不，你先挂
No,you
不，你…
One,two,three.
好 一，二，三
You didn't hang up!
你也没挂
She didn't hang up either.
她也没挂
Okay,no. No,you hang up.
不，你挂 你挂
You!
你挂…
Ross,hi.
罗斯，嗨
It's Rachel.
我是瑞秋
I'm just calling to say that everything's fine.
我只是打来告诉你一切都很好
And I'm really happy for you...
我很替你...
...and your cat.
...和你的猫高兴
Obviously,I am over you.
所以显然的，我已经放下你了
I am over you.
我已经放下你了
And that,my friend, is what they call closure.
而那样，就是所谓的了结
I got a message from you.
瑞秋，有你的留言
Oh,my God! Hang up the phone!
完了，罗斯，挂掉
Give me the phone!
电话给我…
You're over me?
你放下我了？
Oh,God.
天哪
You're over me?
你放下我了？
When were you...
你什么时候…
...under me?
举起我的？
Basically...
基本上…
...Iately,I've....
最近…我…
I've sort of had feelings for you.
我有点对你有感觉
I need to lie down.
好，我得躺下
He broke up with Julie!
他跟茱莉分手了
Go hug her,for God's sakes!
过去抱她啊
-Really? -Really.
真的？ 真的
It's always been you,Rach.
我一直都只要你
Oh,God.
天哪
Listen,I'm sorry I had to work tonight.
抱歉今晚还得工作
That's okay.
没关系
You're worth the wait.
你值得我等
And I don't just mean tonight.
我不只是指今晚
Oh,God!
天哪
Honey.
亲爱的
That's okay.
没关系
No,you just rolled over the juice box.
不是，你压到果汁了
Did you say anything to Rachel about me and the girl from the copy place?
阿甘，你没告诉瑞秋 我跟影印店女生的事吧？
I'm sorry.
对不起
Was I not supposed to?
我不该说吗？
You ended it!
是你要分手的
Because I was mad at you. Not because I stopped loving you.
因为我很气你 不是因为我不爱你了
You still love me?
你还爱我？ 没有
What does this mean? Do you want to get back together?
什么意思？你想复合吗？
Maybe.
不是…也许吧
I don't know.
我不知道
I just,I feel....
我只是觉得…
I can't believe I even thought of getting back together. We're so over!
我居然会想跟你复合 我们根本就完了
Fine by me!
无所谓
And hey! Just so you know, it's not that common.
顺便告诉你 这种事并不常见
It doesn't happen to every guy, and it is a big deal.
并非男人都会这样 这是很严重的
I knew it!
我就知道
Rachel's coming up. Doesn't she look pretty?
瑞秋来了，她是不是很美啊？
Oh,my God!
天哪
This is us getting ready for the prom.
这是我们准备要去参加舞会
We don't have to watch this.
这种带子就别看了
Yeah,we do!
当然要看
Come on!
拜托啦
-Get a shot of Monica. -How do you zoom out?
拍一下摩妮卡 怎么拉远？
There she is!
有了
Shut up! The camera adds 10 pounds.
闭嘴，上镜头会多10磅
So how many cameras are actually on you?
所以是有几个镜头对着你？
Dad,turn it off!
爸，关掉啦
It is off.
我关了
Right,Ross?
对吧，罗斯？
Looking good,Mr. Kotter!
粉帅喔，麦克风头
I can't go to my prom without a date. It's too late.
我没舞伴不能去舞会 时间来不及了
If you're not going, then I don't want to go either.
要是你不去，我也不想去了
I have a wonderful idea.
我有个好主意
You should take Rachel to the prom.
你带瑞秋去参加舞会
We've seen enough. Let's turn it off.
看够了，关掉吧
-I want to see! -Fine,I'm not going to watch.
我想看嘛！ 那我不看，行吧？
Come on,kid. Let's go.
走吧
Are you handsome!
你好帅
Let's show them!
去让他们瞧瞧
-Okay,Dad. -Rachel,ready or not.
行了 瑞秋，不管你好了没
Here comes your knight in shining
解救你的白马王…糟了
再见 奇普，快点
Oh,dear!
天哪…
How do I turn this off?
要怎么关掉？
I can't believe you did that.
你居然真的这样做了
Yeah,well....
我就…
See? He's her lobster!
看吧，他是她的龙虾
No.
不会吧…
You're really not going?
你真的不去？
It's just going to be too hard.
对，我会很难面对
You know,I mean...
毕竟…
...it's Ross.
他是罗斯
How can I watch him get married?
我怎么能看着他结婚？
It's just for the best. You know? It is.
这样最好，真的
Plus somebody's got to stay here with Phoebe.
而且总得有人陪菲比
She's going to be pretty big by then.
到时她的肚子会很大
She'll need someone to help her tie her shoes.
她会需要别人绑鞋带
Drive her to the hospital if she goes into labor.
在她要生的时候送她去医院
You don't have a car.
你没有车
And your license expired.
驾照也过期了
There's so much to do, and I have so little time!
看吧，事情那么多 时间却那么少
Check this out.
你们看
There's a place you can go to rent videos of all the museums.
这里有完整的博物馆录影带
"It's almost as good as being there."
“几乎如同身历其境”
It's better! You can't go to a museum in your underwear.
更棒，去博物馆不能穿内裤
You could,but just the one time.
可以，但之后你会被封杀
We could get videos of the sights...
我们可以去租景点录影带
...get a VCR in our hotel room and never have to go outside!
搬台录放影机就不必出房间了
-lf we do that,we've got to rent Die Hard. -I bet the British version is good!
那一定要租“终极警探”
英国版一定很赞